In this clip of Warrior Training, we're going to start to start to incorporate elbow strikes.
Elbow strikes are use a lot of times in Kickboxing and Thai Boxing to create cuts in the opponent's face so that the fight will be stop prematurely.
This particular elbow that we do in from our fighting position, instead of the traditional fighting position; because I'm going to utilize the elbow strikes, I'm now going to open my hand to make my weapon longer.
This is a downward elbow targeting the middle of the nose and the upper ridge.
So my opponent is here, his centerline is open, from my fighting position, hands open, I step and I'm striking with the pointy part of my elbow and all my weight is dropping down.
All the weight comes down slow to my opponent's face.
Punch, elbow, elbow.
Again, one of the key components to remember, positioning.
Everything starts from your fighting position.
You have to have a good base, a good stance.